RG 098, Department of Agriculture
Connecticut State Library
Department of Agriculture records
1866-1978
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Dept. of Agriculture
2.25 cubic feet
The department’s mission is to foster a healthy economic, environmental and social climate for agriculture by developing, promoting and regulating agricultural businesses; protecting agricultural; enforcing laws pertaining to domestic animals; and promoting an understanding among the state's citizens of the diversity of Connecticut agriculture, its cultural heritage and its contribution to the state's economy.
RG098
Multiple
Historical Note
The Connecticut State Board of Agriculture was established in 1866 under Chapter 65 of the Connecticut Public Acts. The board helped establish the Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station and the Connecticut State College, later the University of Connecticut. It was the forerunner of the present Department of Agriculture, organized in 1925. The department's mission is to foster a healthy economic, environmental and social climate for agriculture by developing, promoting and regulating agricultural businesses; protecting agricultural and aquacultural resources; enforcing laws pertaining to domestic animals; and promoting an understanding among the state's citizens of the diversity of Connecticut agriculture, its cultural heritage and its contribution to the state's economy.
Scope and Content
Records in this collection were created by both the State Board of Agriculture and the Department of Agriculture and include meeting minutes, financial records, newspaper clippings, and scrapbooks
Related Material
RG 002:025, General Assembly. Joint Standing Committee on Agriculture, Accession T001369, Meeting minutes, correspondence, budgets and reports pertaining to consolidation of agriculture departments, 1939-1941.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Dept. of Agriculture; Connecticut. State Board of Agriculture
Subjects:
Connecticut. Dept. of Agriculture -- Records and correspondence; Connecticut. State Board of Agriculture -- Records and correspondence; Agriculture -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Account books; Agendas; Clippings; Minutes; Press releases; Receipts (financial records); Reports; Scrapbooks
Restrictions on Access
Some of these records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
Accession T002779 came from the Commissioner of Agriculture's office to the State Library on February 17, 1979.
Container List
- Accession T002779, 1866-1978
  - 1. Minutes of meetings of the State Board of Agriculture, 1866-1918, 1960-1978 (Box Box 1)
    - 1866 August 1 - 1896 September 10, 1 volume (Box Box 1)
    - 1897 July 1 - 1911 June 29, 1 volume (Box Box 1)
    - 1911 July 19 - 1918 November 19, 1 volume (Box Box 1)
    - 1960 September - 1971 October, 1 volume (Box Box 1)
    - 1971 November - 1976 April, 1 volume (Box Box 1)
    - 1976 May - 1978 December, 1 volume (Box Box 1)
  - 2. Treasurer's book, 1884-1922; 1 volume (Box Box 1)
    Statement of Board's financial account.
    Arranged chronologically.
  - 3. Receipts, 1919-1920; 1 folder (Box Box 1)
    Receipted paid bills.
  - 4. Scrapbook, 1922-1934; 1 volume (Box Box 1)
    Contains clippings relating to agricultural affairs.
  - 5. Clippings, 1976-1978 (Box Box 2)
    Clipping file kept by the department.
    - 1976-1977, 1 binder (Box Box 2)
    - 1978, 1 binder (Box Box 2)
  - 6. Land Preservation Task Force clippings, 1974-1978 (Box Box 2)
    - 1974-1975, 1 binder (Box Box 2)
    - 1976-1977, 1 binder (Box Box 2)
    - 1978, 1 binder (Box Box 2)
    - Report of the Governors' Task Force on the Preservation of Agricultural Land, 1974 December 20 (Box Box 2)
- Accession 1999-012, 1945-1962; bulk 1959-1962
  - 7. Connecticut Soil Conservation Advisory Committee, 1945-1962; bulk 1959-1962; 1 binder (Box Box 1)
    Minutes, agenda, reports. Photograph dated 1945.